Steven Patrick Flynn

Executive
Summary

Bath webpage
Personal webpage
updated Nov 2022

• Training in Microlocal Analysis and Sub-Riemannian geometry. Experience with representation theory of Nilpotent groups.

Research Interest

 Semi-classical Analysis and PDEs on Lie groups and singular (sub-Riemannian) geometries. Inverse problems and Spectral Theory. Mechanics and Mathematical Physics.

Education

- University of California, Santa Cruz, Ph.D., Mathematics, June 2020. Thesis title: "Unraveling Geodesic X-ray Transforms on the Heisenberg Group." Co-Advisors: François Monard, Richard Montgomery.
- University of California, Santa Cruz, M.A., Mathematics, June 2015.
- University of California, Santa Cruz, B.A., Pure Mathematics (with honors; Physics minor) June 2014.

Employment

- University of Bath, Postdoctoral Research Associate, Jan. 2021–present.

 Quantum Limits for Subelliptic Operators

 Funded by the Leverhulme Trust under Véronique Fischer (PI) and Clotilde
 Fermanian-Kammerer (Co-PI)
- University of California, Santa Cruz, Graduate Researcher/Graduate Student Instructor/Teaching Assistant, Sep. 2014–Jun. 2020.

Selected Research Experience

- 2019, Mathematics Sciences Research Institute, UC Berkeley Microlocal Analysis
 Invited as a Program Associate for the Fall 2019 semester.
- 2019, UC Santa Cruz

 Explicit methods for linear and non-linear tomography
 Supported as Graduate Student Researcher on the NSF grant titled above
 (DMS-1814104, 2018-2020, PI: François Monard).

Accepted Publications

- 1. C. Fermanian-Kammerer, V. Fischer, and S. Flynn. "Some Remarks on Semi-Classical Analysis on Two-Step Nilmanifolds" (proceeding) To appear in the Springer INdAM Series (2022).
- 2. C. Fermanian-Kammerer, V. Fischer, and S. Flynn. "Geometric invariance of the semi-classical calculus on nilpotent graded Lie groups." To appear in the *Journal of Geometric Analysis* (2022).
- 3. S. Flynn. "Injectivity of the Heisenberg X-ray transform." Journal of Functional Analysis 280.5 (2021): 108886.

Articles in preparation

- 1. C. Fermanian-Kammerer, V. Fischer, and S. Flynn. Working Title: "A Non-commutative Semi-classical calculus on Filtered Manifolds" See webpage for updates.
- 2. S. Flynn. Working Title: "Tomography on H-type Groups." See webpage for updates.

Invited Talks

- November 2022 Geometric Invariance of the Semi-Classical Calculus on Graded Lie groups.
 - Conference on Noncommutative Analysis and PDEs Link Queen Mary University of London.
- November 2022 Tensor Tomography on H-type groups. Geometry and Analysis Seminar Link University of Bristol
- May 2022 The Heisenberg X-ray transform: A first approximation Inverse Problems on sub-Riemannian manifolds.
 Analysis and Differential Geometry International Seminar Link University of Aveiro
- March 2022 The Spectral Decomposition of sR-Ray Transforms AGeNT Seminar Link University of Bath
- November 2021 Unraveling the Heisenberg X-ray Transform Problèmes Spectraux en Physique Mathématique Link Institut Henri Poincaré
- September 2021 Unraveling X-ray Transforms on Heisenberg group Bath Analysis Seminar Link University of Bath
- April 2021 Unraveling the Heisenberg X-ray Transform Sub-Riemannian Seminars Link. (Online).
- May 2020 Quantizing The Fourier Slice Theorem UC Santa Cruz Geometry and Analysis Seminar.
- January 2020 Integral Geometry on Contact Manifolds Joint Mathematics Meeting, Denver Colorado.
- September 2019 Integral Geometry on Contact Manifolds Mathematics Sciences Research Institute, Berkeley CA.
- November 2019 Noncommutative methods for inverting the Subriemannian X-ray transform on the Heisenberg group

 Mathematical Sciences Research Institute, Berkeley, CA.
- April 2019 Inverting the Heisenberg X-ray Transform
 AMS Sectional meeting, Sub-Riemannian and CR Geometric Analysis, University of Connecticut, Hartford.
- March 2019 Inverting the Heisenberg X-ray Transform Graduate Student Geometry and Topology Conference, University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign.
- June 2018 *The Heisenberg X-ray Transform* UC Santa Cruz Geometry and Analysis Seminar.
- April 2017 X-rays and Heisenberg
 Eastern Illinois Integrated Conference in Geometry, Dynamics and Topology.

Teaching Experience

• University of Bath, Bristol, Imperial, Oxford, Warwick and Swansea (planned)

I am preparing to a graduate level course in Geometric Mechanics to be delivered through the Taught Course Center in the January to March 2023 session. TCC is a collaboration between the Mathematics Departments at the Universities of Bath, Bristol, Imperial, Oxford, Warwick and Swansea. TCC offeres graduate courses to all participating universities, delivered through Microsoft Teams.

• University of California, Santa Cruz

Graduate Student Instructor: As a GSI, I independently taught one lower and three upper division mathematics classes for 20 hours per week concurrently with my graduate studies. I was responsible to give lectures, write exams, assign homework, manage a teaching assistant, assess students' work and distribute grades.

Lower Division:

Summer 2017 Math 3 Precalculus

Upper Division:

Summer 2019 Math 105A Real Analysis Spring 2019 Math 105B Real Analysis Summer 2018 Math 105A Real Analysis

• Teaching Assistant: I have six years experience working as a teaching assistant 20 hours per week concurrently with my graduate program. My duties included delivering axillary lectures, review sessions, grading work/exams and holding office hours.

Elementary Courses:

Math 2 CL (Collaborative Learning), College Algebra (Funded by Title V HSI grant)*

Math 3, Precalculus

Physics 5, 5L, Intro to Physics (Lab)

*For Math 2 CL, I revived additional training to address the needs of students from disadvantaged background.

Lower Division:

Math 11A, Calculus with Applications

Math 19A, Calculus for Science, Engineering, and Mathematics

Math 19B, Calculus for Science, Engineering, and Mathematics

Math 21, Linear Algebra

Math 23A, Vector Calculus

Math 23B, Vector Calculus

Upper Division:

Math 100, Intro to Proofs

Math 105A, Real Analysis

Math 105B, Real Analysis II

Math 152, Programming for Math (Python)**

**I taught students to use Python (in Jupyter) to visualize, formulate and test number-theoretic conjectures, such as the Collatz conjecture.

• Directed Reading Program Mentor

Supervised an undergraduate research project on the isoperminetric problem at

UC Santa Cruz. The student presented their work at the end of the semester. (Spring 2018.)

Funding

Grants

- June 2022 Grant for travel and accommodation to attend the conference "Conformal Geometry, Analysis and Physics" at the University of Washington. Funded by the Clay Mathematics Institute Enhancement and Partnership Program. \$1000.
- January 2022 Travel Grant from the London Mathematics Society to attend the ICM 2022: £400 + accommodation (canceled)
- August 2019 Supported in 2019 as Graduate Student Researcher on the NSF grant "Explicit methods for linear and non-linear tomography" (DMS-1814104, 2018-2020, PI: Francois Monard).
- July 2015 to Present UC Santa Cruz Travel/Research Grants, totaling \approx \$5000.

Fellowships

- September 2021 Fellowship to attend *The Unity of Mathematics: A conference* in honor of Sir Michael Atiyah, Issac Newton Institute: Travel and accommodation
- June 2020 UC Santa Cruz Mathematics Department Summer Research Fellowship, \$3000.
- June 2019 UC Santa Cruz Mathematics Year-End Fellowship, \$4000. Fellowship awarded to support research over the summer.

Awards

• June 2015 - UC Santa Cruz Mathematics Early Academic Achievement Award (\$500 funding award for early completion of Preliminary Exams).

Service

- 2022 Reviewer for the Journal of Functional Analysis.
- 2022 Organizer of the Bath Analysis Seminar, University of Bath
- 2022 Organizer of the University of Bath Postdoc Away Day.
- Fall 2019 Organizer, Graduate Student Seminar, MSRI.
- Spring 2018 Organizer, Graduate Differential Geometry Seminar, UC Santa Cruz.
- Fall 2018 Organizer, Microlocal Analysis Seminar, UC Santa Cruz.

Workshops

Any workshop or school that involved training in a specialized field of math.

- 2022 Winter School: Foliations, Pseudodifferential Operators and Groupoids Mathematical Institute of the University of Göttingen.
- 2019 Introductory Workshop: Microlocal Analysis MSRI, UC Berkeley
- 2019 Subriemannian Geometry and Beyond II University Jyvaskyla (Invited to give a poster presentation).
- 2018 Subriemannian Geometry and Beyond University of Jyvaskyla.
- 2017 Seminaire de Mathematiques Superieures: Contemporary Dynamical Systems, University of Montreal.

• July 2015 - Seminaire de Mathematiques Superieures: Geometric and Computational Spectral Theory, University of Montreal.

Recent Conferences

- 2022 Conference on Noncommutative Analysis and PDEs. London Mathematical Society and Queen Mary University
- 2022 Tomography Across the Scales: Geometrical Inverse Problems Johann Radon Institute
- 2022 Inverse Problems in Analysis and Geometry University of Helsinki
- 2022 AMS-SMF-EMS Joint International Meeting 2022, Special Session in Sub-Riemannian Geometry Université Grenoble Alpes
- 2022 Conformal Geometry, Analysis and Physics University of Washington
- 2021 Pauda Paris Sub-Riemannian Seminar Università di Padova.
- 2021 The Unity of Mathematics: A conference in honor of Sir Michael Atiyah Isaac Newton Institute.
- 2019 Recent Developments in Microlocal Analysis MSRI, UC Berkeley.

Collaborative Visits

- May 2022 -Institut Henri Poincaré. With Clotilde Fermanian-Kammerer. 4 days
- $\bullet\,$ November 2021 Institut Henri Poincaré. With Clotilde Fermanian-Kammerer. 2 weeks

Research Visits

Relevant Skills Softwa

Software Experience: LaTex, Python, C++, MATLAB, Git.